如果你不会用电脑
If you don't know how to use a computer,
我们可以教你
we will teach you here.
现在大多数工作都要求你会基本的文字处理
Most jobs require at least basic word processing skills.
我们尽量使你达到每分钟50字的速度
We try to get you up to 50 words per minute.
我们也提供面试技巧的培训
We also have a course in how to talk to someone in an interview.
例如
Stuff like
雇主需要什么样的求职者
what employers are looking for,
如何把劣势转化为优势
how to turn negatives into positives.
我们还可提供面试用的西服
We can also provide clothes for the interview
如果你需要的话
if you need them.
一直有人来捐皮鞋和西装
People donate shoes and suits all the time.
要是我有  吸毒史
Wh-what if I had a history with...
怎么办
with drugs?
没什么好难为情的
That is nothing to be ashamed of.
我们许多客户都与毒品斗争过
Many of our clients have struggled with addiction,
如果你想戒毒  我们会帮你
and, if you want to get clean, we'll help you do that.
我有小孩怎么办
And what if I have a kid?
没人能帮你照看吗
No one to help you?
要是我上课或是面试时
You know, if I need someone to watch her
需要人看着她
while I'm in class or, uh, on an interview.
你能帮我吗
Could you help with that?
我们不提供幼儿托管服务
We do not provide child care.
事实上  很多人都有这种要求
Actually, it's something that comes up often.
我很希望能帮上忙
I would love to be able to do it.
但我真的没有资源
I just don't have the resources.
不过我们一直想解决这个问题
But it's definitely on the wish list.
好的
Okay.
好的  谢谢
Okay, uh, thank you.
我会再来
I'll be back.
哦  我得接这个电话
Oh, I have to take this.
好的  请再过来  我们就为你安排
Yes, please come back, and we'll get you started.
很高兴认识你  本杰明
It was nice to meet you, Benjamin.
好的
Okay.
奥斯卡
Hey, Oscar.
哦  那太糟了
Agh! Oh, that is too bad.
他们告诉你原因了吗
Did they tell you why?
你知道吗
Well, you know what?
有时  你和那份工作没缘分  但是
Sometimes, you just don't get the job, but...
奥斯卡  我回头打给你
Oscar, I gotta call you back.
收款人  凤凰基金会
一百万美元
本杰明
Benjamin!
本杰明  等等
Benjamin, wait!
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
来人啊  叫救护车
Somebody call an ambulance!
我看你理发是为了什么
Why am I watching you cut your hair?
如果我在家弄
If I do it at home,
就得我自己打扫
I'm the one who has to clean it up.
有朋友在看你自己理发时感到好奇的吗
Does a friend watch you where it's happening, and wonder why?
新生活  新面貌
New life, new look.
那是不是意味着  你喜欢你的新生活
Does that mean you like your new life?
如果你是问你会不会丢掉工作
If you're asking if your job is safe,
那得看你对你手中的病例有何说法
that depends on what you have to say about the file you're holding.
看起来不太像是疑难杂症
It doesn't seem like much of a case.
尽管  我肯定是错的
Although, I'm sure I'm wrong.
确实  告诉我为什么
You are. Tell my why.
这家伙没吃早饭  在大热天
Guy collapsed after being on his feet for hours
徒步数小时后晕倒
on a hot day without breakfast...
还真是匪夷所思
So that's really weird.
急症室没发现什么问题
E.R. found nothing wrong.
然后我决定  我该检查下他的钱包
Then I decided I should test his wallet.
他很有钱
He's rich?
那就是我们接这病例的原因吗
That's why we're taking the case?
不  我们接这病例是因为没人知道
No, we're taking the case because no one knows
他得了什么病
what's wrong with him.
外加他很有钱
And he's rich.
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams.
给她病历
Give her the file.
我只有这一份
This is my only copy.
我的工作方式依赖于一个团队
My M.O. depends upon the use of a team.
当然  那就需要
Definitionally, that involves...
不止一个人
more than one person.
所以我别无选择  给她病历
So I really have no choice. Give her the file.
你雇不起一个团队
You can't afford a team.
亚当斯是免费的[有空]
Adams is free.
我说的是她既有空
And I'm referring both to her availability
又不花钱
and her price tag.
新来的  见见早来的  反之亦然
New girl, meet newer girl, and vice versa.
你说的是  我们喝杯咖啡
You said we were meeting for coffee.
当有人邀请你喝咖啡
Well, when someone asks if you want coffee,
很明显  是有潜台词的
they obviously don't just mean coffee.
等等  你不会以为我指做爱吧
Wait...did you think I was referring to sex?
出去时能拉上百叶窗吗
Would you shut the blinds on your way out?
我以为你是想谈谈
I thought you were referring to talking.
聊医学
Talking about medicine.
准确说来  咱们来聊聊
Specifically, as it refers to the guy
那份病历上的病人  而她到现在还没给你
whose name is on the file she still hasn't handed you.
我不干  豪斯
I'm not working, House.
我在找一份有薪酬的工作
I'm in the process of looking for a paying job.
同时  像你这样
In the meantime, there's no way
爱做好事的人  肯定不会
a do-gooder like you has been volunteering
满大街跑
all over town--
到处喂猫施舍吧
ladling kittens, spaying soup...
在特伦顿有家免费诊所
There is a free clinic in Trenton.
今天把这看成免费诊所吧
Well, think of this as today's free clinic.
只不过得疱疹的流浪汉少点
Only with fewer bums with herpes.
我觉得我们手上这个不算病例
I don't think we actually have much of a case.
我认为不过是脱水
I think it's just dehydration.
上次另一个医生
What happened the last time
告诉你我判断有误时  结果如何
another doctor told you I was wrong about a case?
我丢了工作
I lost my job.
你救了一条命
You saved a life.
有必要做B超检查吗
Is an ultrasound really necessary?
我现在感觉好多了
I'm feeling much better now.
你这年纪突然晕倒
Oh, a sudden collapse at your age
可能是心肌退变
can indicate a deterioration of the heart muscle.
很严重的病
Pretty serious condition.
也可能只是脱水
It can also just be dehydration.
下次  你其实不必布衣打扮
Next time, you could probably drop the undercover act.
我要是西装革履走进去
I walk in in a suit,
他们会全力表现出最好的一面
and they're gonna put their best foot forward.
再说  我也没有西装
Also, I don't own a suit.
你捐了百万美金  自己却连西装也没有
You give away millions and you don't own a suit?
也都捐掉了
I gave those away too.
有一天  我给庭院设计师开支票
One day, I was writing a check to my landscaper,
突然有了觉悟
and it suddenly hit me--
六千美金就为挪走花草  种批新的
$6,000 to take out plants and put in different plants.
这样我就能享眼福了
So I can look at them.
难道不该把钱花到更有意义的事上吗
Shouldn't I use that money to do something important?
你提到钱
And by money,
你指的是你所有的钱啊
you mean all your money.
我一开始捐一千万
I started with 10 million,
随后一想何不捐两千万呢
and I couldn't think of a reason not to give 20,
或四千万
or 40.
我想我一年两万五就够花了
I figure I could live off $25,000 a year.
住单卧的公寓
One-room apartment,
出门坐公交  买东西上旧货店
bus pass, thrift stores,
就买一些必需品
bare necessities.
软件公司依旧是我的
I still have my software company,
等我挣更多的钱  我会继续捐
and when I make more, I'll give that way too.
-这家伙疯了  -他只是慷慨而已
- He's nuts. - He's generous.
他神经系统出了问题
There's a neurological issue.
要把所有东西都捐了
He's getting rid of everything.
他的超声心动图显示他没有心肌病
His echocardiogram is negative for cardiomyopathy.
头部CT没有中风或颅内出血的迹象
Head CT showed no signs of stroke or hemorrhage.
他只有一条裤子
He has one pair of pants.
像他这么有钱的人  一般都会
Most people with his kind of money
把钱花在约克夏身上
are commissioning oil paintings
给狗也画幅肖像画
of their Yorkshire Terrier.
本杰明为了帮助别人
Benjamin is sacrificing
毅然牺牲了自己舒适的生活
his own comfort to help others.
因为对他来说帮助别人就是种享受
That's because helping others is his yorkie oil painting.
这是高尚的品质
That's good.
不是有病
Not sick.
这就是病  太天真了
That's naive and sick.
你要是真的想改变世界
You really want to improve things?
还是得从政策上入手
You do it through policy.
这家伙把钱都捐了  世界能有什么变化呢
This guy empties his pockets, what really changes?
这也对  那些患艾滋病的儿童
That's right, all those babies with AIDS,
他们只是在利用我们
they're just using us.
我父母刚到这里时身上只有八百块
My parents had $800 between them when they got here.
他们节衣缩食  东挪西借
They scraped and borrowed,
以供我们上好学校
so we could go to good schools,
而我卖命地工作学习
and I worked my ass off.
从来没人伸手帮过我
No one gave me a handout.
这鞭策我更加努力
It makes me work harder.
我不同意
Rebuttal.
你又在打什么坏主意呢
What's your evil plan?
我对你的官腔表示抗议
I object to your cynicism.
这是我努力争来的职位
It's been earned.
我就是要抗议这个
That's what I object to.
新院长应该有广阔的胸怀
The new dean of medicine has an ethical obligation
对每一名员工
to come in with a completely open mind
都有一颗包容的心
about all employees.
所以就让我随心所欲一下
Thus letting me blithely run roughshod
至少四个礼拜吧
for at least four weeks.
我想你是打算给他安排一堆检查
My theory is that you're running a battery of tests
让他相信是你救了他的命  之后忽悠他
to convince him that you saved his life,
让他出资把你原来的团队都雇回来
then con him into funding you to hire back your team.
你说啥
What?
你以前的团队
Your old team?
你说啥
What?
接受现实吧
This is your new reality.
你有你自己的办公室
You've got your office.
现在还有邻居
You've got neighbors.
你手下有一名雇员  一名志愿者
You've got one employee, one volunteer.
直到她找到一份有工资的工作
until she finds actual paid work,
或者实在忍受不了你了
or gets sick of you.
我和奇斯还有陶博谈过了
I talked to Chase and Taub.
他们愿意回来
They're willing to come back.
那十三呢
What about Thirteen?
她就算了吧
Not a good choice.
她活不长了  所以她不是长久之计
She's not long term because she has no long term.
她不接你电话  是吧
Not taking your calls?
她会接的
She will.
让那病人出院
Discharge the patient.
他的昏厥无法解释
Unexplained loss of consciousness
有可能是心肌病
could be cardiomyopathy,
大脑缺氧  蛛网膜下腔出血...
global anoxia, subarachnoid hemorrhage--
或者就是脱水
Dehydration.
他打过点滴了  而且已经好转了
He was given fluids, and he got better.
而且我敢说检查结果显示  他是健康的
And I'm sure your tests have come up negative
要不你早让我闭嘴了
or you would have shut me up already,
这就是说他可以回家了
which means he goes home.
还有一个病征
There is a symptom...
他极其慷慨
extreme altruism.
你现在有两条路  豪斯
You've got two choices, House.
你可以承认你的病人
You can recognize that your patient
是一个健康的好人
is just a very nice, healthy guy,
然后送他回家
and send him home,
或者你把慷慨当做一种病征
or you can consider altruism a symptom,
这样  你也不能要他的钱
in which case, you cannot take his money.
让他出院吧
Send him home,
然后再查查
and check with admitting
所有新入院病人的身家
for the net worth of all new patients.
我不会回来的  豪斯
I'm not coming back, House.
严谨点说  你现在就已经回来了
Technically, you're back right now.
你别再给我打电话了
I need you to stop calling me.
头十七条留言挺感人的  但...
First 17 messages were cute, but--
我要重组咱们的团队
I'm putting the band back together.
鉴于你从来没有来过我家
Interesting that you never showed up at my place,
用诚挚的邀请来烦我
what with your love of annoying me
而且你不接受拒绝  这挺有意思
and your inability to take no for an answer.
我猜你脚踝上有追踪器
I'm guessing ankle monitor.
我罪有应得
Guilty as charged,
真的
literally.
我已经不是医生了  豪斯
I'm not a doctor anymore, House.
工作是没了  但不至于放弃这个职业啊
The job went away, but not the profession.
你看着挺健康的  那么...
You look healthy, so...
肯定不是身体原因
that's not it.
你有男朋友了
You met a boy,
或是女朋友
or a girl.
你们俩相爱  想过幸福的生活
Fall in love, wanna be happy.
你决定好好享受你剩下的时光
You decided to... enjoy what time you have left.
你要去泰国
You're going to Thailand.
是女朋友
Girl.
我们打算去米科诺斯
And Mykonos.
其实我喜欢平平淡淡的生活
Turns out I like boring.
不对  你是想过平淡的生活
No, you wanna like boring.
但如果你真的喜欢平淡的生活
But if you actually liked boring,
你在五年级时就应该知道了
you would have figured that out in fifth grade,
因为那时你就很平淡
when you were bored.
别再给我打电话了
Please stop calling me.
不
No.
你专程跑来
You showed up
告诉我  不想我再打扰你
to tell me that you don't want to hear from me.
你言行不一致啊
That's a mixed signal.
我更愿意相信你的行动
I will choose to listen to your actions
而不是你说的话
rather than your words.
行动不会撒谎
They're more honest.
我有点糊涂了
I'm a little confused.
此项测试是用于检测你是否
The test is designed to determine if you're--
不  我是奇怪即要给我做检测
No, I mean your running a test
却又要让我出院
and discharging me.
我到底是不是脱水呢
Was I dehydrated or not?
我觉得是的
I think so.
但是  出于安全考虑
But, out of an abundance of caution,
我的同事自愿为你
my colleague has taken it upon herself
多做一项检测
to do one more test.
好吧
All right.
你让我觉得有点害怕
You scare me a little.
为什么
Why?
我打算申请做
I've been considering
无国界医生
applying to doctors without borders.
去国外待一段时间
Going overseas a while,
对我来说这是很大的牺牲
and that seems like a huge sacrifice.
但...你
But...you--
你不是让她害怕
You don't scare her.
你让她心有愧疚
You make her feel guilty.
你
Oh, you...
你喜欢你的生活方式罢了
you like your life that way it is.
大多数人会尽不放弃身外之物
Most people give the minimum they have to give
以便能享受到更多
so they can enjoy what they have left.
我想我的捐赠底线
I guess my minimum is just...
比大多数人高很多吧
higher than most.
募集反应相和干扰相均正常
Complete recruitment and interference pattern.
他的腿部肌肉没问题
His leg muscles are fine.
我觉得有点不舒服
I feel, uh, funny.
哪里
Where?
胸口
My chest.
你心动过速
You're tachycardic.
你心跳太快了
Your heart's beating too fast.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
病人心动过速  185跳/分
Patient got tachycardic to 185.
我们给他静脉推注了18毫克腺苷
We pushed 18 milligrams adenosine.
他身体肯定有问题
There's definitely something wrong with him.
太好了
Which is awesome.
有病症要医治
Now there's something to cure,
也就意味着我们能得到
which means there's something to be
不成比例的经济回报
disproportionately financially grateful for.
早安
Morning.
给你买咖啡了
Got you a coffee.
谢谢你
Thanks.
心律失常很可能是
Arrhythmia could easily have caused the collapse
造成这位"圣父"晕倒的最初原因
that landed Father Teresa in here in the first place.
没事  我请客
Oh, that's fine. Keep it.
我们昨天检查过他的心脏
We looked at his heart yesterday,
并没有发现任何结构异常
didn't see any structural abnormalities.
我在想是不是长QT间期综合征呢
I'm thinking Occult long QT syndrome?
会不会是惠普尔综合征呢
What about Whipple's?
若是惠普尔综合征
If it was Whipple's,
那就应该会出现神经症状
there'd be some kind of neurological involvement.
难道你觉得与人性相违背的行为不算吗
You don't think defying human nature is neurological?
心动过速  医学症状
Racing heart: medical condition.
滴血的心脏  愚蠢的象征
Bleeding heart: stupid condition.
你这么说是因为你是这么认为的
Are you saying that because you believe it,
还是因为认为他的慷慨并非一时兴起
or because it's in your financial best interest
有助于你骗取他的钱财呢
to think his generosity isn't just temporary?
有人告诉我  有些人就是好人
I'm told that some people are just nice.
我在试着接受这一真理
I'm trying to embrace that wisdom.
过去的几周里
Benjamin's been taking allergy medication
本杰明在服用抗过敏药
the last few weeks.
长QT间期综合征可能是由药物导致的
Long QT syndrome can be medication-induced.
给他用大剂量补液  以清除体内抗组胺药物
Flush him with saline, get rid of the antihistamines,
然后做心电图
then do an EKG.
等等  我去做冲洗吧
No, wait. I'll do the flushing.
收下那两美元
Take the damn $2.00.
那杯咖啡她连一口都没有碰
She hasn't even sipped the coffee.
我非常生气  你知道吗
I just got so angry. You know?
我犯了个严重的错误
So I made a terrible mistake.
现在我试着开始新的生活
Now I'm trying to start my life over.
像我一直希望的那样  去帮助他人
To help people the way I always wanted.
但我的部门预算被缩减
But my department got defunded, and...
错在我
it's my fault.
因为我没有资源来发挥自己的特长
Just can't stand to think of all those patients
而使得那些病人无法获得救治
going untreated because I don't have the resources
这让我难以忍受
to do my best work.
我来帮你怎样
How about I help you out?
你什么意思
How do you mean?
我会给医院捐赠一百万美元
I'll give $1 million as an endowment to the hospital,
并注明是捐赠给诊断科的
earmarked for diagnostics.
我这个投机主义前科犯
I am an opportunistic ex-con
才给你讲了两分钟我的悲催经历
who just gave you a two-minute sob story
这才是我伟大计划的第三步
as step three in my master plan,
你就答应要给我一百万美元了
and you've offered me $1 million,
都已经是第十七步了
which is step 17.
这样不好吗
Is that bad?
我从来不是个遵循道义的人
Ethics are not my strong suit.
假设
Hypothetical--
如果一个性欲狂要为我口交
If I'm offered oral sex from a sexaholic,
我要拒绝吗
do I have to decline?
先别回答
Don't answer yet.
拒绝的话  我们俩都痛苦
Saying no will cause both of us pain.
答应的话  我们俩都欲仙欲死
Saying yes will cause both of us pleasure.
你不能利用性欲狂获得性
You can't take sex from a sexaholic.
你不能给酗酒者提供酒
You can't give booze to an alcoholic,
你也不能接受这家伙的钱
and you can't take this guy's money.
可能症状诊断错了
Could be wrong about the symptom.
我一直在犯错
I'm wrong all the time.
接受病患的钱
Taking money from a sick person
从道义上来说是说不过去的
is ethically suspect at best.
难道我们在加拿大吗
What is this, Canada?
我们的所作所为就是赚病人的钱
All we do is take money from sick people.
我们为此工作
We work for it.
我就是在工作啊
I'm working!
多少钱
How much?
二十美元
$20.
如果真的是二十呢
Well, what if it was?
原则是一样的啊
It's the same principle.
二十还是一百万有什么差别呢
$20, $1 million... what's the difference?
实际上  差别就有一百万那么大
Actually, the difference is pretty much $1 million.
是他开的价  不是我
He came up with the figure, not me.
糟糕
Crap.
我有个终末期肾衰病人
Got a patient with end stage renal disease.
她的心脏承受不了透析
Her heart can't support dialysis.
她需要移植  但是
She needs a transplant, but...
只要谈论与你无关的事  你就神游了
you tuned out as soon as it stopped being about you,
是吧
didn't you?
-什么  -我要走了
- What? - I gotta go.
都是悬而未决啊
It's all moot.
病人可能患有长QT间期综合征
Patient probably has long QT.
也可能他就是个很热心肠的人
Probably just a really, really decent person.
这样的人是存在的吧
They exist, right?
你不能接受这钱  豪斯
You can't take the money, House.
长QT间期综合征不好吗
Is long QT bad?
这种病很难控制
It's a tough thing to control.
要我帮你打电话给什么人吗
Is there someone you want me to call?
我是有想找的人
There's someone I would like to call.
但她正好是不会理我的人
She's the same person who won't take my calls.
我妻子
My wife.
我开始捐献财产后
When I started giving away the money, I--
我曾希望她愿意跟我一起
I hoped she'd want to do it with me.
但她没有
She didn't.
我想他们
I miss them.
我有两个儿子
I have two little boys.
但即使有了家庭
Having a family doesn't exempt me
我也必须承担社会责任
from social responsibility.
但家庭第一
But family comes first.
没错
It should.
我知道这样说很怪  但...
I know that sounds weird, but...
你的亲人
someone who's related to you,
难道就比其他人特别吗
does that empirically make them more special?
难道就应该得到更多吗
More deserving than anyone else?
是啊  家庭是你的责任
Yes, it gives you a responsibility.
我儿子有地方住
My boys have a roof over their heads.
有东西吃
They're not starving.
我按法院要求  付子女抚养费
I pay court-ordered child support,
老实说这笔钱
and, frankly, it's...
远超他们生活所需
more than they need.
世上我最爱的就是他们
I love them more than anything, I just...
但供他们上私立学校  买游戏机
I can't justify buying video games and private schools
对其他挨饿的孩子来说太不公平
when other people's children are starving.
希望有一天  他们能理解
I hope, one day, they'll understand that.
你的手在颤抖
Your hands are trembling.
是因为电极吗
Is it the electrodes?
你痛不痛
Are you in pain?
不痛
No.
怎么回事
What's happening?
我不确定  但显然我们之前想错了
I'm not sure, but it's not what we thought it was.
心律不齐
So...arrhythmia,
昏厥  肌颤
fainting, muscle tremors.
加上  不幸的  精神改变
Plus, unfortunately, mental changes.
我还是认为不是神经问题
I still don't think it's neurological.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
他失去了妻子和孩子
He lost his wife and kids
因为他不肯停止捐赠
'cause he couldn't stop giving money away.
他妻子离开是因为
He lost his wife because she couldn't
她无法接受不做阔太太的日子
accept not being filthy rich.
她也不喝那杯咖啡
She's not drinking the coffee either.
喝  不喝
Drink it, don't drink it.
重点是  我已经给你了
The point is, I gave it to you,
所以我们扯平
So we're even.
扯平
Even?
那只是份礼物
It was a gift.
意思意思而已
An insignificant token.
没什么欠不欠的
There was nothing owed.
这就是重点
That was the whole point.
为什么
Why?
对  为什么
Yeah, why?
她才是不正常的那个
She's the crazy one.
把所有东西都捐出去的人  是圣人
So a guy gives everything away to strangers: sane.
不接受陌生人东西的女孩  是疯子
Girl who doesn't want anything from a stranger is crazy.
你不是陌生人
You're not a stranger.
你这种消极的世界观
And your perverse view of the world
导致你硬要把
is making you force a neurological component
明显的心脏病症说成神经问题...
onto an obviously cardiological--
你父母不够爱你
Your parents didn't love you enough.
所以你想证明你高人一等
So you need to prove your superiority.
或者他们太溺爱你
Or they love you too much,
所以你想表现你很谦卑
So you need to prove your humility.
或只是富人的内疚感
Or it's just rich guilt.
我押最后一个
I'm betting on the last one.
有一大堆的药物
There's a whole list of drugs
可能引起他的症状
that could have caused his symptoms.
我怀疑他是否会花钱买药
I doubt the guy would spend money on drugs
还有那么多孤儿没电视看呢
when there are orphans out there without cable.
总之  他现在已经有所好转
Anyway, he'd be getting better right now,
没有恶化
not worse.
可能是结节性多动脉炎
Could be polyarteritis nodosa.
那会出皮疹
That comes with a rash.
埃可病毒
Echovirus.
可病毒 病毒 毒
Virus, virus, virus, virus...
和他身体症状相符
Fits his physical symptoms.
而且可能
And could,
但不一定会引起人格改变
but doesn't necessarily cause personality changes.
都同意吗
Works for everyone?
开始抗病毒治疗
Start him on antivirals.
亚当斯
And, Adams...
如果你给他治病
when you treat,
把他治好了
and he gets better,
就变身为万恶的资本家
and doesn't give Bob Cratchit Christmas Day off,
你就欠我一杯咖啡
you owe me a coffee.
点左边第三个标签
Click the third tab from the left
找到标有"以往病例"的地方
and find the box that says "previous entries."
会展开按病人姓名和部门排序的
You get a drop-down menu sorted by patient name
下拉菜单
and department.
谢谢
Thank you.
感谢你的帮助
Appreciate your help.
我这么帮你  你又要想多了吧
You're gonna read too much into this, aren't you?
不  完全不会
No, not at all.
我们就到底什么算"想多"
We're gonna fundamentally disagree
有着完全不同的定义
about what it means to read too much into this,
不是吗
aren't we?
完全正确
Yes, absolutely.
我想过你说的话
Look, I thought about what you said,
我觉得你是对的
and I realized you were right.
很好  明早见
Great. See you tomorrow morning.
不  不会
No, you won't.
下午见吗
Afternoon?
我想不出其它意思了
I can't think of another interpretation.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我不能确定
Look, I'm not sure
你到底想要干什么
what you were trying to achieve.
我从来没确定过
I'm never quite sure.
但在我需要帮助时
But you were actually a friend to me
你算得上是我朋友
when I needed it.
我不想回来为你工作
I don't wanna come back to work for you.
但我不应该和你断绝联系
But I was wrong to try to push you out of my life.
电脑出现蓝屏了
Everything has gone blue.
这不是正常现象吧
That's not supposed to happen, right?
等着别动  我来了
Stay there. I'm comin'.
不  你不用来的
No...you don't have to do that.
不过  如果你要来
Although, if you did come,
也许你可以去下湖南天堂
maybe you could swing by the Hunan Palace
给我带点捞面和四川牛肉
and get some Lo Mein and a Szechuan Beef.
那离我家有六英里
That is six miles out of my way.
那好吧
Oh, okay, then.
看来我只好从医院食堂买吃的了
Guess I'll get something from the hospital cafeteria,
也就是我吃每顿饭的地方
which is where I get all my meals
因为我哪儿也去不了
since I can't go anywhere.
好吧
Fine.
我会帮你带食物的
I'll get the food.
你真是个小可爱
You're a peach.
我刚开始做最后一轮普来可那立治疗
I started the last round of pleconaril.
你能帮我个忙吗
Can you do me a favor?
一个忙吗
A favor?
你想让我把它们退回去吗
You want me to return these?
还是捐给别人
Give them to someone?
还是在你自慰的时候穿着它们
Wear them while you masturbate?
我想把它们送给你
I...want you to have them.
这可不是帮忙
That's not a favor.
是买二送一的活动  我没忍住
It was a two-for-one sale. I couldn't resist.
我就是想找个借口买下来
I need to justify buying them.
它们可值一百二十美刀呢
They're $120.
我的车还在商店里呢
My car is in the shop.
我这个月缺钱
I'm short on cash this month.
我承受不起
I can't pay you back.
第一双是一百二十美刀
The first pair were $120.
这双免费
These...were free.
你应该知道我揍了
You do know I punched
上一个招惹我的人吧
the last person that pissed me off?
不会是圣诞老人吧
Was it Santa?
你病人的状况怎么样了
What's your patient's status?
好多了
Better.
我们正准备让他出院
We're discharging him.
很好
Good.
为什么你会在乎
Why do you care?
具体点说
Specifically.
虽然对笼统的回答我也感兴趣
Although I'm curious about a general answer too.
你的病人刚签署捐赠肾脏的协议
Your guy just signed up to donate a kidney
捐献给我的肾衰竭病人
to my patient with renal failure.
他见过你肾衰竭的病人吗
Did he meet your patient with renal failure?
没有  他听见护士们在讨论
No, he heard the nurses talking about her,
说我的病人时日不多了
that she was short on time.
我错了
I was wrong.
别这么说
Don't say that.
豪斯  她真的需要这个肾脏
House, she really needs this kidney.
他没有好转
He's not better.
他的精神状况在恶化
His mental status is declining.
也可能他只是在为另一个人
Or he's doing an amazing thing
做一件伟大的事情
for another human being.
我还以为这是个伦理常识呢
I thought it was an ethical no-brainer
我们不能从病人身上拿东西
that we can't take stuff from sick people.
我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
他还病着呢
He's still sick.
他的症状已经消失了
His symptoms have gone away.
不是所有症状
Not all of them.
为陌生人捐献器官
Offering an organ to a stranger
本身就是一种病的症状
is a symptom.
一年有几十个人
A couple dozen people a year
进行不定向肾脏捐献
make undirected kidney donations.
对  但他们中有多少
Yeah, how many of them are also in the process
在不断抛弃自己的财富呢
of pauperizing themselves?
如果这哥们主动在战场牺牲
If the guy threw himself on a grenade,
他就会是个英雄
he'd be a hero.
这能拯救一条生命  你干嘛斤斤计较
If it saves a life, who cares?
是你斤斤计较
You do!
昨天  你还持完全相反的意见
Yesterday, when you made the exact opposite argument.
只要我有一丝胜算
If there's even a chance I'm right,
那让他捐献肾脏就是很危险的
it'd be dangerous to give his kidney to someone else.
比完全肾衰竭还危险吗
More dangerous than complete renal failure?
我的病人需要他的肾脏
My patient needs this.
就是现在
Now.
你为什么要捐献肾脏
Why do you wanna give away your kidney?
每一年这个国家里有七万人
There are 70,000 people in this country
在肾脏移植的等待名单上焦急等待
on the active waiting list for a kidney,
一年只有一万身亡的人
and less than 10,000 dead people a year
会捐献
to give them one.
如果我们每年能杀掉六万多人
If only we could kill 60,000 more people a year,
世界将变成美好的人间
all would be golden.
我会给你捐款的
I'll give you your money.
看见了吧  他疯了
See? Crazy.
成为活体捐献者有风险
Being a live donor has risks.
我查过了
I looked it up.
风险是四千分之一
The risk is 1 in 4,000
我可能在手术过程中死去
I could die during surgery,
也就是说  如果我不捐献肾脏
which means, if I don't donate,
我就是认为自己的命比别人珍贵四千倍
I'm valuing my life at 4,000 times someone else's.
我并不想被手术刀划开
It's not like I want to be cut open and
被取走一块
have a part of me taken out.
但我有两颗肾脏  那个女人一个也没有
But I've got two, and this woman has none.
没有肾脏  她会死的
She'll die without it.
很有逻辑性
Perfectly logical.
有精神问题的人也可以有逻辑
People with mental deficiency can be logical.
就像疯子可以没有逻辑
Just like sane people can be illogical.
肾脏捐献事件是你唯一用来证明
This kidney thing is the only evidence you have
他还有病的证据
that he's sick.
我会同意让他捐献
I'm gonna let him be a donor.
豪斯医生
Dr. House,
这不是病症
It's not a symptom.
等你确信我健康了再回来吧
Come back after you're convinced that I'm healthy,
我会把钱捐献给你的
and I will give you your money.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
在他出院之前我们还有时间做最后一项测试
We have time for one more test before we move him.
什么测试
What test?
随便什么测试  只要能证明
Whatever test will prove
他的表现是由埃可病毒可病毒病毒引起的
there was an echovirus-irus-irus,
现在也没有痊愈  这很明显
and he's not cured, obviously.
我一直在说这可能是惠普尔综合症
I've been saying all along this could be Whipple's.
会引起心律失常  颤抖
Causes arrhythmia, tremor,
以及精神变化
and mental changes.
不是什么好想法
Bad idea.
他没有关节痛
There's no joint pain.
亚当斯去哪里了
Where's Adams?
我们以为这例病例已经结束了
We thought the case was over.
她有场求职面试
She has a job interview.
她为什么在这里呢
Why is she here?
因为我打电话让她来的
Cause I called her.
更大的问题是  你为什么会听话
Bigger question is why that worked.
我过来是因为我太闲了
I'm here because I have time
而你又遇到棘手的危机状况
and you have a crisis and I--
没时间合理讲述故事了
We're too busy for rationalizations.
病人抛弃锦衣玉食
Patient made a big downgrade in his personal life.
他可能吃得不那么健康
He's probably not eating all that healthy.
会是镁缺乏吗
Magnesium deficiency?
等他们把他带回房间
Wait until they take him back to his room--
抽血  做个大范围电解质检查
draw blood, do an expanded electrolyte profile.
不用  他没有
No, he hasn't had
焦虑或是失眠
anxiety or any trouble sleeping.
我认为是惠普尔综合症
I think it's whipple's disease.
馊主意  他没有关节痛
Bad idea. He doesn't have joint pain.
关节疼痛虽然是常见症状但并非决定性的
Joint pain is common, but not definitive.
惠普尔综合症能够解释其它所有症状
Whipple's explains all of his symptoms,
包括人格改变
including the personality change.
并且会对抗生素有反应
And it would respond to antibiotics,
这也是为什么他感觉好多了
which is why he started to feel better.
但这并不意味着他病好了
Which doesn't mean he's not still sick.
你刚才是对的
You were right.
如果无法为自己的理论辩护就毫无价值
Counts for nothing if you can't defend it.
订一间操作室
Book a procedure room.
做上消化道内窥镜检查并做PCR检测惠普尔综合症
Do an upper endoscopy and run a PCR test for whipple's.
负罪感
Guilt.
你对离去有负罪感
You feel guilty about leaving.
没错  你的渺小
Yes, I think that little of you
在于我的伟大
and that much of me.
没有我你一无是处
You're nothing without me.
不是离开我
Not leaving me.
而是远离人性
Leaving humanity.
我是要跟我的女朋友一起
I'm going with my girlfriend.
我的爱人
The woman I love.
去享受生活
To have fun.
你想让我感到内疚
You're trying to make me feel guilty
因为你正在这拯救生命
because you're saving lives here.
而我认为这很棒
And I think that's great.
我很自豪曾是其中一员
I'm proud to have been a part of it,
但是...现在...
but...now...
我只想快乐生活
I just wanna be happy.
没人会在希腊不愉快的
Oh...no one's unhappy in Greece.
前几周才出现的
It just appeared in the last few weeks.
他在学校都拿不了笔了
He's having trouble holding a pencil in school.
痒吗
Does it itch?
最近发生什么不同的事了吗
Do anything different lately?
买了新棒球手套或是新装修了厨房吗
You get a new baseball glove, a new kitten?
我的邻居弄了个游泳池
Well, the neighbors put in a pool,
他最近总去那
so he's been spending a lot of time over there.
不过  如果水里有什么的话
But, well, if it was something in the water,
那应该会到处都是  不是吗
it would be everywhere, wouldn't it?
确实是水里的东西
It is in the water.
他对氯过敏吗
He's allergic to chlorine?
不是...
No...
他对夏丁香过敏
He's allergic to summer lilac.
那是我的润肤露
That's my lotion.
不可能在游泳池里
And it's not in the pool.
没错  是在他手掌上
No, it's on the palms of his hands.
那游泳池里的应该是你邻居家的女儿
In the pool is the neighbor's daughter.
或是你邻居家的辣妻
Or the neighbor's hot wife.
这是润滑剂
Here's some lube.
不好意思  你的视力是没救了
Sorry. Too late for your eyesight.
内窥镜并未在小肠内
Endoscopy didn't reveal any lesions
看到任何病灶
in the small intestine.
我正在做PCR测试
I'm running PCR test now.
在我办公室找到的
Found it in my office.
看上去像个礼物
Appears to be a gift.
不会有好事的
That can't be good.
该死
Damn it.
是你给她找的面试机会
You got her the job interview.
本该能结束这一切的
And that was supposed to be the end of it.
我...不接受施舍
I...don't take charity.
对你挺好  你这笨蛋
Good for you! You loon.
我不喜欢欠别人什么
I don't like owing people things.
你要么就是没安全感
So either you're so insecure
让你觉得需要时刻掌握主导权
that you feel like you need to always have the upper hand,
要么就是你自尊心过强
or you're so arrogant
帮你个忙都会冒犯到你
that the notion of a favor is insulting to you.
或者是因为你的家庭
Or it's your family,
某种移民情结什么的
some kind of immigrant pride thing.
我打赌是最后一种
I'm betting on the last one.
我就是不喜欢而已
I just don't like it.
那会让我觉得...有点恶心
It makes me feel...icky.
就这原因吗  恶心
That's the reason? Ickiness?
你从没想过分析其中的原因吗
You never even tried to analyze this?
这比那到处送礼的更疯狂
It's even crazier than the gift thing.
豪斯...
House...
没有发现惠普尔养障体DNA
There's no sign of tropheryma DNA.
不是惠普尔综合症
It's not Whipple's.
好吧...能做的都做了
Well...we did what we could.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure you wanna do this?
放松
Relax.
对此我甘之如饴
This is gonna make me very happy.
辛普森医生
Dr. Simpson.
心率140  血压正在下降
Heart rate's 140, pressure's dropping.
给他腺苷  马上
Get him adenosine, stat.
病人状态不稳定  手术取消
Patient's unstable. Surgery's off.
再次出现心律失常
Arrhythmia's back.
他正在用肝素  目前暂时稳定
He's on heparin and stable for now,
但这样可能会有
but this could put him at risk
中风或者血栓的风险
for stroke or embolism.
也许他被蜘蛛咬了
Maybe he got bit by a spider.
症状可能需要三天时间才能表现出来
The symptoms can take up to three days to manifest.
那应该有局部疼痛的症状
He'd have localized pain.
轻链沉淀病
LCDD?
一般都会损伤肾脏
Almost always hits the kidneys.
福曼医生
Ah, Dr. Foreman.
也许你能帮帮我们
Perhaps you can help us.
我拿不定主意是在新英格兰医学杂志上
I can't decide whether to take out an "I told you so" Ad
做个"我早告诉你了"的广告还是老派一点
in the New England Journal or stay classy
直接把它喷涂在你的车上
and just spray-paint it on your car.
你不用参与这个病例了
You're off the case.
这似乎有点反应过度
That seems like an overreaction.
你给他下药了
You dosed him.
你无法忍受失去他这个病人
Couldn't stand to lose him as a patient,
因此就伪造症状来证明你是对的
so you faked his symptom to prove you right.
这太白痴了
That's idiotic.
对不起
Sorry.
不用道歉
Don't apologize.
我不知道你是被权力冲昏了头还是得了妄想症
I don't know if you're power crazed or paranoid,
不过她是对的
but I know she's right.
这关系到两条人命呢
Two lives are in the balance here.
豪斯  我为你工作了七年
House, I worked for you for seven years.
我知道你是怎么行事的
I know how you operate.
因此当我看到某种症状在你需要的时候
So when I see symptoms magically show up
奇迹般出现时...
right when you need them--
我当了你七年的老板
And I was your boss for seven years.
我知道你是怎样一个细心多疑的人
And I know what a suspicious, micromanaging hard-ass you are.
我为什么要这么做
Why would I do this now?
尤其是考虑到你还能把我立刻送回监狱
Knowing you can send me right back to jail?
你对他做了什么
What'd you give him?
什么都没有
Nothing!
反正你也没法证明
You can't prove otherwise.
那何不做个明智的决定呢
So why don't you do the smart thing here?
你不用参与这个病例了
You're off the case.
你不能再接触这个病人
You no longer have access to this patient.
你不能让他这么做
You can't let him do this.
他是老大
He's the boss.
而且他没说错
And he's right.
我觉得你是确定
I assume you dosed the patient
病人有神经系统问题
because you're really certain
才给他下的药吧
he has a neurological condition?
我觉得你把我的行为
I assume you're interpreting my actions
往善意的方面理解
in the best possible light
是因为你没得到那份工作
'cause you didn't get the job?
你和朴克之间怎么了
What's with you and Park?
没事
Nothing.
我希望我的手下说谎也要像个样子
I expect my people to lie better than that.
你送她礼物无非是出于
Either you're getting her gifts because
你想博得她的好感  这很令我厌恶
you want her to like you, in which case I don't like you.
要么就是想戏弄她
Or you're getting her gifts to screw with her,
这样  我倒是可以向你传授
in which case, I will be teaching you
我的独家秘籍
my secret homey handshake.
我当时就是觉得
I just...I thought it was interesting
她不肯接受那杯咖啡很有趣
she couldn't accept that coffee.
我想看看能进行到什么程度
I wanted to see how deep it went.
那么现在呢
But now?
现在我只是想赢
Oh, now I just want to win.
那个盒子里是什么
What was in the box?
礼券
Gift certificate.
水疗的票子
The spa.
这还达不到效果
Nah, that's not gonna do it.
她这习惯从小就有了
You're up against a lifetime of training.
如果你想赢  你得做些
If you wanna win, you gotta do something
她无法回报的事情
she can't possibly reciprocate.
你应该把她的神经官能症推向一个极限
You gotta push her neuroses to the point
让她自己觉得自己疯了
where even she thinks that she's crazy.
再帮个忙
One more favor.
我保证永远不再打扰了
Then I promise, I'll leave you alone forever.
也可能我是骗你的
Or I'm lying.
不管怎样  这事
Either way, it's more interesting
总比你现在干的有趣
than whatever you're doing now.
有什么我能效劳吗
Can I help you?
我是他妻子
I'm his wife.
我们分居了
We're separated.
听说他病了
I heard he was sick.
我想来看看他
I just... wanted to see him.
他是要捐肾给个素不相识的人吗
He's giving a kidney to someone he's never met?
他是这么打算的
He wants to, yeah.
我听他谈起过你
I know he's talked about you.
和你分开后他一直单身
He's been alone all this time.
能见上你一面
I'm sure it would mean a lot to him
对他意义深重
to see you.
我想和他白头偕老
I wanted to spend my life with him, but...
但我想要他爱我胜过别人
I need to feel like he loves me more than other people.
想要他能更宠爱自己的孩子
Like he loves our kids more.
或许是我自私了
Maybe that's selfish.
我还是走吧
I should go.
那是我妻子吗
Was that my wife?
不知道
I don't know.
你是那个肾脏捐助者吗
You the guy, the kidney donor?
发生点状况
There was a problem, but...
不过我会再尝试下的
I'm gonna try again.
还是捐个原来那位女士吗
Um...to give it to the same lady?
她很需要
She needs it.
好吧  那算了
Okay. Never mind.
等等
Wait.
你有什么需要吗
What do you-- what do you want?
没事  只是
Uh, it's nothing. It's just...
我得了多囊性肾病
I have polycystic kidney disease.
我需要做肾移植
And I need a transplant,
而且他们说我时间不多了
And they say I don't have much time,
我听说你有捐献的意向
so when I heard that you were willing,
我只是
I just...
你给别人我也很高兴
But I'm glad it's going to someone.
我会给你的
I'll give it to you.
但你已经答应给别人了啊
But you already promised it to someone else.
我还有一个
I have another one.
救人一命胜造七级浮屠
Saving one life is good.
救两人命胜造十四级浮屠
Saving two is better.
你两个肾都捐了会死的
You give away two kidneys, and you die.
我能靠透析活上好几年呢
I could live on dialyses for years.
没错  但最后你还是得死
Yes, and-- and then you die.
那样我就能捐其它器官了
And then I could donate my other organs.
心脏  肺
Heart, lungs.
我能救四  五个甚至更多的人
I could save four or five more lives.
福曼得找个诊断医师来
Foreman's gonna need a diagnostician.
这病人疯了
This guy is crazy.
心律失常  肌肉震颤
Arrhythmia, muscle tremors,
对  还有精神变化
And, yes, mental changes.
如果他心脏没有破裂
If his heart doesn't rupture,
他很可能挖出来送给别人
he's liable to rip it out and give it away.
这噪音
You know, the "Down" vibe in here
完全毁了我《查理的天使》的幻想
is totally ruining my Charlie's Angels fantasy.
你这发型也不咋地
And that haircut isn't helping, either.
这症状看着像格雷夫斯病
It seems like graves disease
或是其它什么甲状腺疾病
Or some other thyroid issue.
她现在算是团队的一员吗
Is she on the team now?
是长期的吗
Like, forever?
他入院时的甲状腺素水平
His thyroid levels were within normal range
在正常区间
when he was admitted.
可能是柯萨奇B病毒
Could be coxsackie b virus.
或心包炎
Or pericarditis.
会是卟啉症吗
What about porphyria?
没有出现皮疹的话有些牵强
It's a little weird without the rash,
但是其它症状符合
but it fits all of his other symptoms.
如果是急性间歇性卟啉病
And if it is acute intermittent porphyria,
那就能解释为什么他的症状一再复发
that would explain why his symptoms keep recurring.
虽然不太可能  但至少有可能性
It's unlikely... but it's possible.
还有什么
What else?
我说还有什么吗
I said what else?
现在好多了
There. That's better.
还有什么可能
Now, what else?
好吧  如果仅此而已的话
Well, if there's nothing better than possible,
就死马当活马医吧
then possible gets upgraded to probable.
我去给他用血红素
I'll start him on hematin.
不  还是我去吧
No, I'll go.
你的答案是什么
So what's the answer?
你现在算是团队的一员吗
Are you now on the team?
是长期的吗
Like, forever?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想去订做些T恤
Cause I was thinking of ordering t-shirts.
豪斯  我不知道
I don't know...House.
我该怎么做呢
I mean, what am I supposed to do?
我受训成为一名医生
I trained to be a doctor.
我懂得如何妙手回春
I know how to take someone's pain away,
懂得如何叫人起死回生
How to make a stopped heart beat again.
我们救活过孩子们
We've brought people's kids back.
救活过丈夫们
Their husbands...
那么  你是觉得愧疚吗
So...guilt?
没错  你说对了
Yes, you were right.
你总是对的
You're always right.
只是我...
I just...
我有救死扶伤的能力
I have the skills to help people.
我可以只为了一己之乐
Is it okay for me to walk away from that
就一走了之置身事外吗
because I...want to just have fun?
显然不能
Obviously not.
病人怎样了
How's your patient?
她几小时前去世了
She died a few hours ago.
十三回来了
Thirteen is back.
没有部门  没有资金
No department. No money.
你还能骗得她帮你工作
And somehow, you managed to con her into hanging around.
天生我才
I have a gift.
怎么了
What?
这是一个骗局
It was a con.
病人是装的?
The patient was faking?
不  是我造成的
No, I was.
我编造借口收他入院
I brought him in here under false pretenses
为了得到他的钱
just to get his money.
我随便订了几项检查
I ordered a bunch of random tests
留他住院
to keep him here.
其中一个是脑CT  会用到
One of them was a head CT, which uses...
碘造影
Iodine contrast.
你认为他对碘过敏
You think he's allergic to iodine?
又不对
No, again.
不要打断我
Just don't interrupt me.
十三说对了
Thirteen was right.
是甲状腺问题
This is a thyroid issue.
他患的是普卢默病[毒性甲状腺腺瘤]
He has Plummer's disease.
他的甲状腺有个结节
He has a nodule in his thyroid.
结节分泌额外的激素
It produces excess hormone.
其量不足以在检测中显示异常
Not enough to test abnormal,
但却超过了大脑的耐受限度
just more than his brain is used to.
使他变得不理性的慷慨
Just enough to make him irrationally generous,
使他不能耐受热
make him vulnerable to overheating.
然后你又给他身体里灌进大量碘
Then you pumped his body full of iodine
一下将他打入甲状腺毒症状态
and kicked him into thyrotoxicosis.
我说了不要打断我
I said don't interrupt.
没错  你说对了
But, yes, you're right.
切掉那个结节  他就会好的
Take out the nodule, he'll be fine.
过去了两天  一次手术
Two days, one surgery.
既然你已经病愈  我可以接受赠款了
I now accept, that you're all better.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
是你让我生病的
You made me sick.
你早就病了
You were already sick.
我只是让你病得更重而已
I just made you much, much worse.
说正事  钱
Seriously...the money.
不打算给我了  对不对
You're not giving it to me, are you?
面对死亡的时候
When you're facing death...
会想到以往忽视的事
some things come into focus.
我妻子
My wife.
你爱你的家人  想要他们回来你身边
You love your family. You want them back.
你的利他主义一直都是病征
Your altruism was always a symptom.
不  不是  我还是会坚持...
No, it wasn't. I'm still gonna...
多施予少收取  少到什么地步
Keep less? How much less?
足够宠坏你的孩子
Just enough to spoil your kids?
不是
No.
难道他们需要钱甚于结核病人
But they need it more than people with TB
甚于印尼盲眼的孩子
or children in Indonesia with no eyes?
甚于有一颗金子般的心的诊断师吗
Diagnosticians with hearts of gold?
我不想给你钱  是因为你是个混蛋
I don't wanna give you money because you're an ass.
我上周也这么混呐
I was an ass last week.
我爱我的家人
I love my family.
我想和他们在一起
I want to be with them.
这不能说明我是个坏人
That doesn't make me a bad person.
对
No.
只说明你是个健康的人
It makes you a healthy person.
修理厂来电话
My mechanic called.
说修车款有人付了
He said the work's been paid for.
你提到车还在修理店
You mentioned your car was in the shop.
那可是四千五百美金
That's $4,500.
微笑  说谢谢
Smile and say thank you.
不然我给你装GPS
Or I get you G.P.S.
你赢了
You win.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的车有人给修了
Your car is getting fixed.
你预测正确  她果然上钩了
You're right. She went for it.
干得好
Good work.
明天要我捎你来吗
Need a lift tomorrow?
你的车不是还在修
'cause your car is still in the shop.
我不接受施舍
I don't take charity.
只是很高兴这事终于结束了
I'm just glad it's over.
所谓结束  是不存在的
Nothing is ever over.
十三
Thirteen.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
又闹什么  豪斯  我饿死了
Now what? House, I'm starving.
我没开玩笑  你被解雇了
I'm not joking. You're fired.
明天不用来了
Don't come in tomorrow.
豪斯
House...
我可以接受无处可去的人
I can work with people who've got nowhere else to go.
需要证明自己的人
People who got something to prove.
喜欢疑难病例的人为我工作
People who just get off on weird cases.
可我不能接受一个为我工作
What I can't work with is someone who's here
只为了不受良心谴责的人
so she doesn't have to feel bad.
你想拯救我
You're trying to save me.
对  你的渺小
Yes... I think that little of you
在于我的伟大
and that much of me.
好吧
Okay.
再见  豪斯
Bye, House.